In Toronto's
war on crime.
the worst offenders
are pursued by the detectives
of the Specialized Criminal
Investigations Unit.
These are their stories.
So there I was.
centre field.
Exhibition Stadium.
drunk as a skunk. no pants.
Dave Stieb on the mound.
So I says.
"Pitch me one. Davie.
I'll end your no-hitter."
Oh. Benny.
you are such a liar.
- Don't you believe me. Prim?
- Prim?
Hey. it's Maggie.
you dimwit.
I've slept with
half the men in here.
so don't you dare
call me Prim.
Sorry.
- I'll tell you what.
Let me try on that swanky
gold ring of yours
and then I'll call it square.
Easy. Cleopatra.
Mark Anthony here needs
his afternoon nap.
Well. I guess
you must be the. uh. asp.
I wouldn't be alive
without you.
- Just doing my job.
- I've met other social workers.
Ethan. they judge. You care.
Hmm.
Which is why
I got you something.
Kyle. you know
I can't accept gifts.
- It's not that kind of gift.
- What is it?
The answer to the question
you keep asking people.
Watch Online Movies and Series for FREE
www.osdb.link/lm
Ethan. What's up?
You alright?
You knew.
Didn't you?
All this time?
Hey. W-why don't you
get in the car?
We'll talk about--
I don't wanna get
in your car.
I want the truth.
♪ Be sure it's true
♪ When you say
♪ I love you
We accommodate all religious
days in advance
and on Sunday nights.
your mom can sip
a cocktail or a boost.
While she enjoys music
she loves. Rose and Dario
come by once a month
to see their friend Benny
and entertain.
They're a real hoot.
♪ 'Cause these words
♪ Were spoken
♪ I love you
♪ Yes. I do
Keep it clean. ma.
Someone's gonna have
a heart attack.
Whoa. ma.
Can you believe
a mug like your dad
tickling the ivories
like that. Matteo?
Apparently. Liberace used to
roll grissini to get
better at piano.
That true?
No. Benny.
♪ When you say. I love you
♪ It's a sin to tell a lie ♪
There you go.
God. You smell good. honey.
Hmm. I can't get you
out of my head.
I know. Benny.
I know.
- Mm-hmm.
There you go.
Where are we going?
It's so cold.
Prim.
How'd we get here. baby?
His name's Benny Donahue.
He came to Gracewood a year ago.
- Who found the body?
- One of the staff workers.
In house doctor
pronounced him dead.
Was about to wheel him inside.
but I told him
to back away and called you.
Hmm. Poor guy. it was only
minus 12 last night.
Would've taken three. four hours
for the hypothermia to take him.
So the home executive director
said that
this was not Benny's first
late night outing.
Apparently.
they found him wandering
various parts of the park
over the last month or so.
This wasn't an accident.
Uh. slippers match these indents
in the turf.
but the indents are pointed.
Made with the balls of the feet.
If Benny wheeled himself out.
he'd be digging his heels in
dragging. not pushing.
He didn't do this.
Someone wore his slippers.
Someone brought him
out here to die.
That mark on
his left pinky finger.
Frostbite starts at the very end
of our extremities
and works backwards.
That mark's above the knuckle.
Hmm. Benny was wearing a ring
and he was allergic to it.
The blue skin.
especially around his mouth
and fingernails.
that could just be the cold.
but it might be cyanosis.
Lack of oxygen.
- Opioid overdose?
- Hmm. it's possible.
it was freezing cold last night.
Look at these sweat marks.
Low exposure. overdose.
Combination of both.
Now let's call it in.
Who would do such a horrible
thing to a sweet old man?
Excuse me!
Is this going to be much longer?
Well. at least she didn't snap
her fingers at us.
That was a good catch.
Hey. Mark. can I ask.
what are you doing here?
Am I a suspect?
Sorry. it's a force of habit.
I was doing what I do
every morning before work.
Visiting my mom.
Hi. Mummy.
- Hi.
How're you doing?
It's a beautiful day out there.
Next of kin as listed here
is Benny's son.
Dr. Sheldon Donahue.
Does he visit? Is he here a lot?
Don't know.
I've never met him.
Hmm.
Did Benny have a personal
care worker?
Yes.
Gia Frank. she's off today.
Okay. Well. we're gonna
need her number.
Uh. we'd also like. a...
a list of all of
Benny's visitors. please.
Okay.
Here it is.
There are no visitors
for an entire year?
Not even his son?
- That's what the log says.
- You don't find that strange?
- Not at all.
The lives of senior citizens
are lonelier and sadder
than the public cares to know.
Was Benny an opioid addict?
The file here says he had
a prescription
for buprenorphine.
Benny has medication
for a chronic back pain.
It was bad.
He could barely walk.
Well. either way. I don't
think Benny wheeled himself out
into the dark with
a head full of opioids.
And as I'm sure
you're well aware.
any stories of negligence
surrounding a care home.
well. they seem to snowball
in the press.
so. Ms. Malboeuf.
your best look right now
is your complete
and total cooperation
with this investigation.
G-G-G-Gia!
That's cute.
Straight to voicemail.
Hmm. Bateman.
"Remember who you are."
Hmm. An affirmation?
He was reading Moll Flanders.
That's a story about repentance.
Maybe... remember who you are
was a sign of
a guilty conscience.
Could be a threat
from Benny's killer.
It's. uh. lipstick.
so perhaps it belongs
to the elusive Gia?
Oh. let's get a car on our.
uh. missing care worker
and in the meantime.
let's. you and I.
deliver the bad news in person.
Find out why Dr. Andrew Donahue
wasn't visiting his dad.
Uh. Doctor. excuse me.
I'm Detective Henry Graff.
this is Detective
Francesca Bateman.
Toronto police.
- Hi. how can I help?
Well. Doctor. we've just come
from Gracewood Manor.
I'm so sorry to inform you
that your father.
Benjamin Donahue.
passed away this morning.
You're joking.
My father died nine years ago.
Uh...
Doctor. do you
recognize this man?
Never seen him
before in my life.
So. this is not
Benjamin Donahue.
No. Wait. or. are you saying
this guy was pretending
to be my dad?
It's probably just
a clerical error.
We're very sorry
to have bothered you.
- That's a nice piece.
- Mm-hmm.
Solid gold.
Where'd you get it?
- A friend gave it to me.
- Hmm.
Just gonna go grab my loupe.
Okay.
So. uh. how much
you want for it?
You know what?
I change my mind.
Actually think
I'm gonna keep it.
What's your rush?
Hey! Get back here!
Benny Donahue. John Doe.
whatever his name is.
suffered from NF1. neurofibromatosis.
You can see the telltale
cafe au lait marks on his torso.
I also found a fibroma
growing in his spine.
No wonder
the poor guy could barely walk.
I think Benny was a smoker
trying to quit.
Nicotine patch. although
strangely. his lungs were clear.
And. Detective. you were right.
the discolouration
around his pinky finger
is most likely
a reaction to the nickel used
to fortify a 24-karat gold ring.
- You have a cause of death?
- Cause of death is hypothermia.
but the massive amount
of buprenorphine
in his system didn't help.
Well. that many
opioids in his system.
Benny wouldn't have made a peep.
- Also--
- Oh. the blue fingernails.
No. Fingerprints.
He has none.
They're burned off. chemically.
What did our victim do for work?
- Well. we were hoping
you could tell us that.
because everything
the retirement home
has on him is fake.
Hmm. hunch at the neck.
tennis elbow.
Maybe he worked with his hands?
Mm-hmm.
Who are you. Benny?
Uh. uniforms have a 20 on Gia.
- I didn't steal anything.
- No.
Is that because
of your religion?
Um. no? Why?
The menorah on your cupboard?
No? Nothing?
Rings no bells?
What? The crappy
brass candlestick?
It was Benny's. wasn't it?
You see.
despite his phony Irish name
we know that Benny was suffering
from neurofibromatosis.
a. uh. genetic condition
often seen in Ashkenazi Jews.
He gave it to me.
I was good to him.
He wanted to thank...
Thank me.
What about the ring. Gia?
Was that a gift. too?
God. I don't have
his stupid ring.
Where were you last night
between midnight and four AM?
- Booty call. Chad something.
- Hmm.
- You can check my Bumble.
- Yeah. you seem real beat up
to learn that Benny died.
- Kinda comes with the job.
- Like dementia?
When did you know he had it?
Dementia. that...
That wasn't in his chart.
Oh. it wouldn't be. would it?
The symptoms had just started.
That's why he asked to borrow
your lipsticks
so he could write.
"Remember who you are"
on his mirror.
And that's why he wore
the nicotine patch.
to stave off memory loss.
Benny wanted to stay lucid.
Okay.
There may have been some signs.
- We're getting somewhere.
- Look. some people
lose their memory.
other people lose their filter.
Say things they wouldn't
normally say.
it was hard to tell.
Okay. so what kind of stuff
was Benny saying?
He used to always talk about
some girl named Prim.
And how he once pinked a job
from the lucky?
Or some guy George Choofallo.
Chuffallo?
George Chuvalo?
The boxer?
I guess.
Said that's why he lasted
so long against Allah?
Ali. Muhammad Ali.
Maple Leaf Gardens. 1966--
Look. I didn't know
if any of it was true.
but he was always very
entertaining.
Mm-hmm.
Okay. Gia. where's the ring?
I threw it out. Honest.
I tried to sell it
at the Sherburn Pawn
and the guy got really weird.
Grabbed me. It was actually
like. really scary.
so bye-bye ring.
What else can you tell us
about this ring?
It was gold. was it heavy?
Any distinguishing
features. markings?
- Yeah. actually.
it had a carving
of a bull on it.
Wasn't like I was gonna wear it.
I'm not even a Taurus.
No. you wouldn't
wear that ring.
It would clash with
your new orange jumpsuit.
What?
Pinked a job means
he made a suit with great care.
Hunch on the neck.
tennis elbow.
Benny was a tailor.
Yeah. maybe
the Lucky was a shop.
Huh. Tom Ford.
as we live and breathe.
- Who?
Tom Ford. The. uh. tailor?
Designer?
I thought he was the guy
who made cars.
No. that's me. Henry.
- What's your name?
- Joey.
Joey. Joey. you ever
seen this man before?
- Nah.
We'll we're gonna need
a record of employment
or pay stub. maybe a number
so we can call your boss.
Come on. bro.
Some guy hands me cash
to come in here and like--
- And like. you know. what?
Keep the lights on.
don't burn the place down.
Almost sounds like
a direct quote.
Okay. cool. That's cool.
Tell me. Joey.
just-just between us.
where in the store
are you not allowed to go?
Backup?
Good talk.
Look at that Judy.
the middle seams on them.
What have we got?
That's a Colt 1911.
It's a beautiful piece.
Serial number's filed off.
tape on the grip.
No fingerprints.
access to sports celebrities.
It wasn't a bull
on Benny's ring.
it was a cow with horns.
A sign of strength
and equilibrium.
You're thinking
our Benny's mafia?
I am.
And judging by his...
...gun collection.
I think our Benny...
was a hitman.
Benjamin "Benny" Cohen.
AKA Benny the Gent.
AKA the Mensch.
Never married.
never had any kids.
Gia said he used to talk about.
uh. a woman named Prim.
Could be an ex-girlfriend.
but so far. we haven't found
anyone with that name.
- Yup.
First Jewish hitman
in the Toronto mob.
I've been hearing stories
about Benny the Gent
since I was a rookie.
Kind of like the Boogie man
of the underworld.
An old commander told me once
that when Benny
was 20-something.
a mob boss refused
to pay him.
so Benny sneaks into
the mob boss' house.
puts a gun next to his
sleeping son's head.
and pulls the trigger.
Boss comes running in.
Benny looks at him and says.
"That's an extra zero
on the end of what you owe me.
How rich do you wanna make me?"
This is exactly
why it's gonna be hard
to narrow down a suspect.
Benny was a person of interest
in at least 15 murders
over the course of 40 years.
It's a lot of bad blood.
a lot of underworld debt to pay.
But since 2015. we have nothing
on Benny Cohen.
Find out which of our guys
has eyes on the Calabrian Mafia.
And see if they can narrow down
who exactly
would want this man dead.
I mean. as far as we know.
uh. Benny stopped working
for the mob nine. 10 years ago.
Nobody's hired a hitman
in a wheelchair.
Detective Novak.
if you were to take
a wild guess.
which one of these guys
would want Benny dead
after all of these years?
- None of 'em.
That's the thing.
they're all getting older.
moving to Florida.
Calabrians have been
very quiet lately.
Well. it's unlike
the mafia to bear a grudge.
Sure.
But Benny. Benny's freelance.
He worked for all four leaders
of the Calabrian mafia
in Toronto. You think
your answer's up there?
You have to talk
to all those guys.
But. here's a word to the wise.
no one's gonna admit
to even knowing Benny.
Let alone employing him.
You want one
of the big boys to talk?
You need to prove he had
a solid connection to Benny
and I mean. concrete.
That's not going to be easy.
This is why criminals
love Canada.
We are one of the most opaque
jurisdictions in the world
when it comes to identifying
the president of a company.
numbered company
owned by numbered company.
Another title search.
another ghost.
All we need
is a connection to Benny.
If-if we can find
any kind of payment.
we can cross reference it
with mob-style killings
at the same time.
Okay. but without
a clear paper trail.
I won't be able to tell
which family paid what.
We need to put names
to these numbers.
Hey.
Look. I just wanted
to say. uh...
And maybe
it's none of my business.
but. um. if you ever
need anything.
or you wanted to talk.
I'm here. okay?
You know that right?
It's dementia.
Early onset.
Oh. God. Mark.
I'm so sorry.
You know.
it just happened so quickly.
One day. she's living
an independent life.
the next she's stuck
in the middle of the 401
because she can't
remember how to drive.
Jesus. Geez...
How's she doing now?
She's forgotten
most of the basics.
Names. dates. doesn't even
remember me half the time.
My brother and I compete
with each other
to try to get her
to say our names.
He sings her Abba.
I bring her Baskin Robbins
praline & cream.
Once in a while.
she remembers us.
Says. "Thank you. baby."
or "I love you. Mark."
Makes everything worth it.
Hey.
Just got. uh. Benny's
bank records released.
Should be up on the server.
Okay. now we're talking.
Huh.
$10.000 deposited monthly
going back years.
The last deposit was a week ago.
Depositor?
Numbered company.
surprise. surprise.
No name attached.
but it was briefly set up at
a retail space in Mississauga.
And it was sold by...
agent's name is Matteo Galatti.
Galatti.
Son of mob boss Dario Galatti?
AKA Il Macellaio.
The Butcher.
His signature dish
was flaying people
who betrayed him.
Dario used his numbered company
to keep Benny's
payments off his books.
Why would Dario be sending
monthly payments
if Benny was retired?
Maybe Dario
got sick of paying
for a hitman
who couldn't hit anymore.
Especially one
with an occipital lobe
that was turning him
into a chatty Kathy.
Hey. buddy. You better
get your story straight.
Homicide is sniffing around.
You put it up like this
with your right hand.
this hand. you turn it
toward you.
And with your left hand. you
turn it away from you. alright?
Detectives. you could've called.
I would've answered.
Ah. we saw that
the shop was open.
Took the chance you'd be here.
I'm a little peckish.
So. uh. the murder police
show up unannounced.
while I'm working with my family
with a line down the block.
You know. people could start
thinking the wrong thing.
Oh. what would
the wrong thing be?
That a bakery
used to be a butcher?
Il macellaio.
Sofia. belleza.
Come. my dear.
- So what can I do for you?
- Look. Dario.
we understand your need
for sweet old man act.
but it's not for us.
We know who you are
and that ring on your pinky
says it loud and clear.
We just wanna know
where you were the night
that Benny Cohen was murdered.
So you know who I am. huh?
If that were true.
you'd know that Benny and me.
we were like brothers--
Well. Cain and Abel
were brothers.
Well. if Abel
saved Cain's life.
then things would've
turned out different for them.
What. so Benny
saved your life?
Matter of fact. he did.
10 years ago.
I had a home invasion.
These-these two lowlifes tied up
me and my son. Matteo.
and they robbed us. And when
they figured out who I was...
They couldn't risk
leaving you alive.
Exactly.
And if Benny hadn't shown up
exactly when he did...
So I have nothing
but love for that man.
So much so that I pulled strings
and I paid to put him
in a private care home
when he couldn't walk
properly anymore.
Well. you also paid him
10 grand a month
for the last 10 years.
The numbered company
that paid Benny
was connected to a building
that your son sold.
My son is a real estate agent.
He has nothing to do
with my business.
Nothing.
- When was the last time
you saw Benny? Did you ever
visit him in his suite?
- I don't remember.
- You don't remember?
Oh. that's an interesting
choice of words.
considering Benny was suffering
from dementia.
Benny had dementia?
Yeah. and you know what?
We heard it was starting
to make him
a little bit talkative.
I don't know. maybe you
had some secrets with him
that you wouldn't want spilled?
I didn't know
that Benny had dementia.
It's kinda good that
he went the way he did.
it was probably
a kindness of God.
It-it would've killed us
to watch him go through that.
Enough to take matters
into your own hands?
The night Benny died.
I was at
the Mount Dennis Legion.
Charity poker game.
You know what?
Here.
Enjoy 'em... on your way out.
Well. his grief seemed real.
but. uh. I once
knew a mob guy
who swore he never
beat his wife.
even when I found him
standing over her dead body.
Yeah. well.
empty visitor's log
has the mob written
all over it.
Still begs the question. though.
Who else was left off?
So you're still
saying that Benny had
no visitors
for an entire year?
I showed you
the visitor's log.
Okay. see.
that's the thing about being
married to the mob. Charlotte.
It makes telling the truth
a little harder. doesn't it?
Mob boss shows up
with his best friend.
tells you to look after him.
Well. I bet you're
gonna do what he says.
No. we get it.
These are scary people.
But you...
You run a tight ship. huh?
Look at that. Jealous.
So what are the names?
- To be clear.
all I did was agree
to keep the log empty.
Okay. so who
do we not know about?
A few weeks ago. my assistant
didn't get the memo
about not entering
Benny's visitors.
She entered a name into the log.
I arrived and--
Deleted it.
What was the name?
I don't remember
the last name.
but the first name's Ethan.
So. no Ethans associated
with mob hits in the 90s.
And nothing in the aughts
or the teens.
Nothing in Hamilton.
nothing in Montreal.
What about civilian murders?
Maybe this wasn't
connected to a mob hit.
Okay.
Whoa.
Uh. not exactly a civilian.
but narcotics officer.
Vincent O'Hagen.
was murdered on Lake Simcoe.
Uh. case file says that Benny
was briefly a suspect
due to the gun that was used.
but then it got
attributed to a string
of B&Es. but...
Survived by his wife.
Angela O'Hagen.
and son. Ethan O'Hagen.
Okay. Ethan O'Hagen works in
corrections as a social worker.
So we got the son of a.
of a slain police officer.
working with hardened criminals.
His father's death. unsolved.
Maybe Ethan hoped to find out
who killed his father
by working with the only people
in the world who would know.
Other killers.
Maybe he finally found
the right suspect.
So. Ethan.
who told you that Benny Cohen
killed your father?
- Benny who?
Ah. "Benny who."
Your father was a cop
and he was murdered at a fishing
cabin on Lake Simcoe.
Wasn't even on the job.
just trying to relax.
catch a few carp.
It was a senseless. awful murder
and you wanted revenge.
- I said I don't know any Benny.
Well. the staff
at Gracewood Manor
said that you visited Benny
in his suite. three weeks ago.
Do you wanna keep
playing this game?
One thing I've learned
on the job.
cellmates talk.
One of them squawked. huh?
You've been doing this job.
what. five years?
That's a lot of dangerous
men you talk to.
Did you ask them all?
Wouldn't you?
If you thought you could find
out who killed your father?
Sure. he was your hero.
It became an obsession.
You wanted justice.
Hero...
Right.
He was a decorated officer.
He--
- Look.
Everything
you're saying is true.
Yes. I wanted to find
my father's killer
and yes. I planned
to kill him when I did.
So...
Ethan.
Did you?
I couldn't.
I went to see Benny
at the home.
I confronted him
about everything.
It was so weird.
Benny didn't duck from it.
He admitted to killing
my father.
He was regretful.
Atoning. even.
He told me things about
my father I never knew.
Like what?
Like the fact that my dad
was on the mafia payroll.
Excuse me?
Yeah. I. uh...
I threw up after
Benny told me that one.
But after I thought about it.
it all made sense.
My dad had been taking money
from the Galatti family
since he graduated
from police college.
Ethan. did Benny tell you why
the mob wanted your father dead?
Yeah. I hear some stash house
that got held up back in 2010.
Yeah. James Town towers.
The masked assailant. uh.
took down three
Calabrian soldiers
and two innocent bystanders.
One of them. a six-year-old kid.
It was my father.
Apparently.
Dad felt he wasn't being
paid enough. so. uh...
He decided to get himself
a little cash bonus
before Christmas.
I spent my whole life.
trying to get justice
for a good man that. um...
Well. he never existed.
Who was Vincent O'Hagen's
partner who was killed?
Ethan knew we were coming.
Maybe he still
has a partner in the force.
Jesus.
Okay.
God gave him one face.
he gave himself another.
What can I get you.
Detective Novak?
Uh. is your.
is your husband here?
- No.
- Oh.
Can I give him a message?
Yeah. sure.
I just wanted to say
how sorry I was to hear
about Benny Cohen. Really.
Benny was a good man.
Knew how to keep his mouth shut.
At least until recently.
I heard he was getting
a little sloppy?
- You want to get to the point?
Sure. If Benny
happened to mention anything
to you or your husband
about me.
I suggest you just forget it.
Or at least
keep it to yourselves.
There are plenty more photos
where that came from.
Walsh. come on. you gotta pass
the ball sometime!
I'm open!
- Put it up. put it up!
- Hopkins. it's all you.
Don't let me down.
Detectives.
any news on Benny Cohen?
Uh. Ethan O'Hagen.
uh. your former partner.
Vincent. um...
Benny killed Vincent.
Ethan found out
and wanted revenge.
Ethan? Guys.
There is no way.
You and Vincent were partners
for what. eight years?
Were you close?
- Come on. guys.
Your partner's your family.
So how'd it feel
when Ethan told you
Benny had killed your family?
It was 15 years ago.
Wounds heal.
Uh. if you guys
are done trying to.
trying to shake me down
for Benny Cohen's murder.
I'm just gonna
get back to my game.
Wounds heal.
Well. why-why would
you say that wounds heal?
This wasn't...
about revenge. Bateman.
No. we were wrong.
This is about betrayal.
You knew Benny
was the first suspect.
And you also knew your partner
was on the tape. didn't you?
Question is. when did you
find out he was dirty?
Before or after?
- Look. detectives--
- If somebody murdered
my partner.
it would take 500 years
for my wounds to heal.
But you seem awfully copacetic.
Copacetic with maybe
a little tinge of... guilt?
What-what
are you suggesting?
Officially. Vincent
was on sick leave. yeah?
But he was actually in hiding.
wasn't he?
The fishing cabin where
he was killed. Lake Simcoe.
That cabin was owned
by your old captain.
You all had access to it.
Vincent's murder was
attributed to a string of B&Es.
so we stopped looking at the mob
because you made sure that
that happened. Right. Novak?
'Cause you couldn't
have anyone asking
how Benny knew
where Vincent was
because Vincent didn't tell
anybody. not even his wife.
No. But partners?
Partners always know
more than the wives.
Okay. look.
this-this is insane.
Benny Cohen knew
your deepest darkest secret
and we believe you killed him
so he wouldn't share it.
No. No.
For 15 years. For 15 years.
I never touched that guy.
I didn't have to.
- What do you mean?
Look. just to be clear.
I'm not saying that I gave up
my partner that night.
Th-This is...
This is all hypothetical. right?
- Sure.
Okay.
Hypothetically.
let's say...
someone very frightening
does threaten your wife
and your children.
and all you need to do is...
give an address.
A dirty cop goes down.
And your family stays safe.
Right?
Let's say you are terrified.
And let's say that you do it.
It all goes down.
you wake up the next morning
and your wife
brings you pancakes.
And then she tells you
a funny story
about leaving the key
in the lock overnight again.
And then you realize
you are never gonna be safe.
Not without insurance.
So you got insurance.
You tracked Benny.
you followed him.
and you got a secret on him.
What. Novak?
It's over. Benny's dead.
You wanna tell us the secret?
I guess it
doesn't matter anymore.
Benny Cohen was
having an affair.
With Rose Galatti.
Dario Galatti's wife.
And I got pictures to prove it.
Rose Galatti and Benny Cohen.
These were Novak's
insurance policy.
- Yes. they were.
- Lemme get this straight.
Uh. Vincent O'Hagen
robs a mob stash house.
kills five people.
The mob hires Benny Cohen
to retaliate.
Benny threatens
Vincent's partner
to find out Vincent's location
and Novak gives it up.
A cop served up to the mob
by his partner?
This is gonna be a garbage fire.
Ah. it's a dirty cop
who killed a kid
at a stash house robbery.
- I can't hear the difference.
I'm just saying. look.
I kinda feel for Novak.
I mean. look. if somebody
threatened my kid...
I don't know what I would do.
Uh. but Novak is not admitting
to anything just yet.
But it won't take much
to prove now that we know.
Okay. Leave it with me.
I need to start
making some calls.
God. is it gonna be
a long night.
Theo. please. if you can stay
and talk this through with me.
Mm-hmm. Of course.
I was thrilled to get out
of that dinner.
We need to find
Benny's killer.
Now. I need to be able
to assure my bosses
that no more
police were corrupted
in the making of this movie.
- Well. Dario Galatti.
our suspect number one.
Mafia have a code.
You fool around
with the boss' wife. you die.
And more than that.
Dario trusted Benny
as if he was his own blood.
Gave him a ring
that normally would only go
to a made man.
It wasn't just a gift. it was...
It was a show of loyalty.
an act of love.
Now. imagine that outsider.
the one that you've treated
like a brother.
has been sleeping with your wife
for your entire marriage.
Bye-bye Benny.
Do we know where Dario
was that night?
Alibi's rock solid.
but he's the boss.
They seldom have blood
on their hands.
Great we're back
to a button man.
Who is the new Benny
in the Calabrian mob?
Yeah. no worry.
We're on it.
Good. I want this over.
Thank you for the ride.
my love.
It's fine.
I know you don't like driving.
Hey. Matteo.
before Benny died.
did you talk at all?
Did he say anything strange
or out of the ordinary?
- What do you mean?
- I don't know.
I'm just wondering
what he was thinking.
The day before. he asked me
to come visit him. but I...
I didn't have time.
I feel bad now.
- Don't feel bad.
Benny wouldn't want that.
Grazia. amore.
Marco. the Ghost. Moretti.
Luka. Lucky. Ferraro.
Why does these sound
so improbable?
Hmm. because it
doesn't line up.
Well.
I meant their names. but. uh.
what're you talking about?
Benny's death.
You know. if we're right
about the motives.
then this was personal.
This wasn't about business
or. uh. rivalry. or greed.
This was betrayal
of a Shakespearean proportion.
You think Dario
did it himself?
It was too personal not to.
Maybe. except.
uh. Il macellaio.
I mean. pushing an old man out
in the cold to freeze to death?
No. it's a little tame
for a man
who was known
for flaying people.
You know. it almost looks like
the work of a civilian.
- Like his son. maybe?
- Yeah. but I thought Matteo
wasn't following
in his father's footsteps.
Yeah. except Benny
was sleeping with his mother.
humiliating his father.
and maybe that was enough to...
Bring him back home.
Pull him back in?
As you can see. the old owners
didn't like cheap things.
And there's nothing cheap
about this view.
Or these floors.
These babies.
- Blonde maple?
Hand-milled?
That's very good.
- He likes to show off.
- I do.
Especially this little guy.
Do you mind?
Why don't you go check out
the wine cellar?
I'll be down in a second.
Detective.
I'm not sure
if you've heard.
but I don't bake.
Maybe not. but.
well. you did assault a man
when you were 15 for
insulting your father. was it?
And on the night
that Benny Cohen died.
your car was a block away
from Gracewood Manor.
Seems Orwell was right.
Big Brother is watching.
Well. he can watch
what he likes.
because I was home
asleep that night.
So. your car
just wandered off?
Benny saved my life.
He was like an uncle to me.
And I've seen that trick before.
you've been playing it
on my family for years.
Get a new one.
That photo is real.
so we could get a warrant
for the GPS to corroborate it.
or you could just
tell us the truth.
Save everyone a lot of trouble.
I was home. I swear to you.
Matteo. wait.
Did Benny tell you something
before he died?
Did he try to...
pull you aside. maybe?
No? No. why does everyone
keep asking me that?
Who's everyone?
You know what?
You wanna keep chatting?
Talk to my lawyer.
We're done.
Okay. Graff. what's going on?
Well.
kid just showed his hand.
We're closed!
Well. we're not here
for the crostini.
as delicious as they are.
Ma. you're
almost ready to head home?
If you're looking for Dario.
he's not--
We're not here
for Dario either.
We'd like to talk
to you and your son.
And let's hope
for all our sakes
that this conversation ends
before your husband arrives.
Ah. there he is.
Prodigal son.
I told you this afternoon.
talk to my lawyer.
We will. We just wanted
to clear a few things up first.
Yeah. I find baking
an interesting choice of front
for organized crime. hmm?
Bread.
Mana.
Food from the gods.
All made possible
by a reaction of yeast
feeding on sugar. a fungus
getting rich off the sweet
of the innocent.
Carnage in history
created by something as simple
as mixing
flour with water.
You see. baking has a recipe.
and the mafia has a code.
Strict rules of loyalty
and retribution.
And if those rules
aren't followed
as closely
as the recipe. well...
it's mayhem.
- But I can't hope but notice
that brown mark
on your hand. Matteo.
- My hand?
- Yeah. you have another one
on your neck. probably have
a few more on your chest.
might wanna see a doctor.
- I did.
They said they're just
birthmarks.
Well. that's because
you didn't know
that one of your parents
had neurofibromatosis.
It's passed down from
a parent to a child.
- Detectives... please.
- My parents don't have that.
Ma?
Is that what Benny had?
That's why
he had trouble walking.
He had a tumour in his spine.
Ma. What are you saying?
I think you know
what she's saying. Matteo.
Maybe you've always known it.
deep down. that Benny
is your biological father.
And you. Prim.
Primrose.
the girl that Benny
could never stop pining for.
You know. when I found out
that Benny had been drugged.
I assumed the killer was just
wanting to keep him quiet.
but it was really an act
of kindness. wasn't it. Matteo?
You knew Benny had to go.
Before Dario found out
the truth.
Because loose lips.
they sink ships.
But even so. you didn't
want Benny to suffer.
'Cause you loved him.
didn't you?
Like only a son can.
- What? No!
Your car was a block
away from Gracewood
the night that Benny
was killed.
You can't account for your
whereabouts on that night
and now. look at that.
we have a motive.
- No. please--
- I think it's about time
we call your lawyer.
- No! Ma-Matteo wasn't driving
his car that night. I was.
I took it out of the driveway.
he has nothing to do with this.
Matteo. please. go wait
in the front. alright--
No. I'm not going anywhere.
Please. someone explain
to me what is going on?!
- Benny was saying things.
Secret things.
Things that...
if Dario found out--
Dario would have
to honour the code
and kill his beloved friend
in the most gruesome
way possible.
If Benny knew
what he was doing.
betraying the promises
we made to each other.
he would have done it himself.
You don't know that.
You can't know what
was in his mind. No one can.
And dementia or not.
these people are still in there.
They still appreciate kindness.
They still feel love--
So what?
Let him be butchered?
When you work for my husband.
he puts a card in your hand
and lights it on fire.
And says. as this card burns.
so will you burn alive
if you betray me.
And he means it.
So you tell me.
what was I supposed to do?
Let my son be burned alive?
Let him see his mother die?
Let my husband torture
Benny to death?
Oh. so you just left him out
in the cold instead?
- It wasn't like that.
- No?
I went by his side.
I played our favourite song.
Poured him his
favourite scotch and.
and made it so that
he wouldn't feel pain.
And I held his hand
as long as I could
before...
What I did was a mercy.
And maybe so.
But it was also murder.
Please. Detective.
let my mother go.
Okay. Take me. We'll say
that it was an argument.
A debt that
Benny couldn't pay.
We'll say that I did it!
If my father finds out
about this...
- If Father finds out what?
What's going on here?
Dad.
Let's... let's go outside.
let them finish up. yeah?
- What's going on here. Rose?
What do you think
Dario's gonna do
now that he knows
who Matteo really is?
Gonna stick with the code?
Destroy his own son?
Ah. I hope not.
Codes. vows. words.
There's one thing you learn
on the job. it's that...
Everything can be broken.
difuze
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org